Dorothy Thompson Papers
Dorothy Thompson Papers
- Notes and research material
  - Notes and research materials, alphabetical
    - Sweden and Finland
      - Notes, 1954-1955; 3 items (Box 132)
      - Research materials, 1954-1955; 29 items (Box 132)
    - United States notes, 86 items (Box 132)
- Manuscripts by others
  - Manuscripts by others, By author
    - Allen, Jay "Town Meeting", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Barakat, George M. Speech at the overseas convention, typescript copy; 2 items (Box 133)
    - Bethmann, Erich W. "Muslim-Christian Cooperation in Morocco", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Beveridge, William "Planning Under Democracy", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Bottome, Phyllis "The American Hitler", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Brandt, Karl Questionnaire-Nazi Germany, original typescript; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Brecht, Bertold "Kinderkreuzzug", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Bridges, Constance "The Divine Émile", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Brown, Don "So This is America", published; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Bruning, Henrich Questionnaire-Nazi Germany, original typescript; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Chamberlain, William Henry "Farmers for Freedom", published; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Cooper, Ralph E. "Man's Enemy-War", original typescript; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Culbertson, Ely "The A B C Plan for World Peace", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Cuneo, Ernest "Commencement Address", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 133)
    - De Porte, Barbara
      - "An Ideal Citizenship for an Ideal State", original typescript; 1 item (Box 133)
      - "An American Pilgrimage in France", original typescript; 1 item (Box 133)
      - "The French Socialist Party", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Deutsch, Julius "Jugenderziehung", original typescript; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Drucker, Peter "Schriftliche Hausarbiet in der Geographie", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Eder, Jeanne "War-Time Life in Switzerland, 1939", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Ererod, Oluf "Report on Travel in the United States and Canada", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Fairchild, Ellen "Persephone", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Fodor, Marcel W.
      - "Modern Condottieris", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
      - The Little Entente, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
      - Shift in power, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Fueloep-Miller, René "The Voice of Prophesy", original typescript; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Gardner, Clinton "Prospectus for Magazine X", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Gleichmann von Oven, Alexander "Pan Europa Heute", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Groedel, Franz "Health Palace for New York", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Grierson, Margaret "The Wedding", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Guérard, Albert "World Democracy or a New Axis?", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
    - Gunther, John
      - Newspaper article on Hitler, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 133)
      - "Inside Africa" Chapters 1-23, 34-46, galley proofs; 1 item (Box 133)
      - "Inside Africa" Chapters 24-27, galley proofs; 1 item (Box 134)
      - "Inside Africa" Chapters 28, 29, 32, 33, 36-42, galley proofs; 1 item (Box 134)
      - "Inside Africa" Chapters 30-31, galley proofs; 1 item (Box 134)
    - Hildreth, Kay "Present Schools: Good or Bad?", typescript; 1 item (Box 134)
    - Hipschman, Donald "A Man from Main Street", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 134)
    - Jameson, Storm "A Cup of Tea for Mr. Thorgill", galley proofs; 1 item (Box 134)
    - Johnson, Willis and Lorena "Tomorrow's Johnny Will Learn to Read", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 134)
    - Kent, Ann A. P. "My Appeal for Fairness", original typescript; 1 item (Box 134)
    - Knickerbocker, H. R. Hitler Germany articles 1 through 6, typescript copy; 8 items (Box 134)
    - Kortner, Fritz "Memory of a Hero", original typescript; 2 items (Box 134)
    - Kurz, Herman "O.G.P.U. (Tscheka)", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 134)
    - Landman, Henry J. "Three Year High Schools and Colleges for Bright Students", typescript copy; 2 items (Box 134)
    - Landon, Alf "Our Foreign Relations", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 134)
    - Lane, Rose Wilder "Desert Sands", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 134)
    - Lania, Leo "Why Hitler Lost the War", original typescript; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Lavanoux, Maurice "Vitality in Religious Art", original typescript; 2 items (Box 135)
    - Littell, Norman "International Investment Law Conference", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Lookaround, Mrs. Angus "I Live in a Museum", published; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Love, Betty B. "The Fugitive Teacher", original typescript; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Malik, Charles "The Dialect of Co-Existence", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Mann, Thomas
      - "Manifesto to the Civilized World", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 135)
      - "Richard Wagner and the King of the Nibelung", original typescript; 3 items (Box 135)
      - "To the Civilized World", original typescript; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Mathews, William R. "Memorandum on Background and Experience in International Reporting and Editing", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Meyer, Mrs. Eugene
      - "New Social Horizons", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 135)
      - "Popular Leadership in a Scientific Era", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Michaelis, Karin "The People Around Genia", original typescript; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Morgan, Margaret Spofford
      - "General Background for a Survey of the Christian Revival", original typescript; 1 item (Box 135)
      - "Religious Effects of the War in Britain", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel newspaper article on German Nationalist Papers, original typescript; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Muhafez of Zahle speech, original typescript; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Muller, H. J. "Radiation and Human Mutations", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Nichols, William "Person to Person Editing for 11,000,000 Families", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 135)
    - O'Connor, Johnson "Aptitudes of the Minorities", original typescript; 1 item (Box 135)
    - Page "Plan for Enduring Understanding Between Capital and Labor", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 136)
    - Palmer, Frances "And Four to Grow On", galley proofs; 1 item (Box 136)
    - Platts, P, K. "Civilization and Schools", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 136)
    - Priess, Jack J.
      - "The History of Camp William James", pp. 1-50 original typescript; 1 item (Box 136)
      - "The History of Camp William James", pp. 51-125 original typescript; 1 item (Box 136)
      - "The History of Camp William James", pp. 126-206 original typescript; 1 item (Box 136)
      - "The History of Camp William James", pp. 207-301 original typescript; 1 item (Box 136)
    - Rauschnig, Hermann
      - "Ein Grosser Friebe und das Prinzip der Neutralist aet", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 137)
      - "The Aims of Hitler's Foreign Policy", original typescript; 1 item (Box 137)
      - "The Reich's Deathly Weakness", typescript; 1 item (Box 137)
    - Ressa, Alphonso
      - "The Society of Tomorrow", pp. 1-49 original typescript; 1 item (Box 137)
      - "The Society of Tomorrow", pp. 50-102 original typescript; 1 item (Box 137)
    - Rodorancki, C. P. "The Great Work of Civic Readaptation in Greece", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 137)
    - Romanoff, Panteleimon summaries of five short stories, original typescript; 5 items (Box 137)
    - Rosenstock-Huessey, Eugene
      - "A Soldier in the Larger Sense", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 137)
      - "Surrender to Whom?", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 137)
    - de Roussy de Sales
      - Raoul Diary, 1938; typescript copy; 1 item (Box 137)
      - Raoul Diary, 1939; typescript copy; 1 item (Box 137)
      - Raoul Diary, 1941; original typescript; 1 item (Box 137)
    - Rubenstein, Marion
      - "Zorah Yoder" I-V, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 137)
      - "Zorah Yoder" VI-X, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 137)
      - "Zorah Yoder" XI- XV, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 137)
      - "Zorah Yoder" XVI-XX, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Zorah Yoder" XXI-XXV, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Zorah Yoder" XXVI-XXX, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Zorah Yoder" XXXI-XXXV, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Zorah Yoder" XXXVI-XXXVIII, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
    - Salama, Zaki Egyptian feminist union, original typescript; 1 item (Box 138)
    - Schoalfield, Lucille D. "Why is There a Shortage of Scientists?", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
    - Schroeder, Eric speech, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
    - Schwarzwald, Eugenie
      - "Die armen Kinder de Reichen", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Eine neue vokabel", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Erklärung der K P D zum Reichstagbrand", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Es Lebe de Protektion", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "First Encounter with Death", original typescript; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "First Encounter with Death", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "First Encounter with Death", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "First Love", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "First Love", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "The First Love Letter", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "The First Love Letter", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Die Fröhliche Schule", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Gornah", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Das Neldentum einer neuen Zeit", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Kuhwarme Milch", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Der lange und der kurze Rock", typescript copy (Box 138)
      - "Der Lebensluft der alten Schule", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Der Mantel, der Brotkorb und der Affe", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Die Mädchen", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Dottoressa Montessori", typescript copy (Box 138)
      - "Neues Heldentum", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Die Perfetke", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Rekordrummel und Heroenverekrung", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Der Salathund", typescript copy; 2 items (Box 138)
      - "Schwarzer Optimismus", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Der Unsichtbare Lehrer", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Die Verjungung des Säuslings", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Wer Nat meine Bücher", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Wert des Lebens", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "Wie Eltern erzogen werden", typescript copy (Box 138)
    - Sheean, Vincent
      - Book review "The Wilder Shores of Love", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "The Island Chain", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
      - "The Mahatma's Lesson", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
    - Shelby, Gertrude Mathews "Deporté", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
    - Sherwood, Robert E. Speech, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 138)
    - Smith, Roy "Germany Revisited", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 138)
    - Spring, Powell "Spiritual Re-armament", original typescript; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Stoneman, William "An Epigraph", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Stesch, Benjamin "Arrows in the Hands of a Giant", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Strachan, Alan "A History of the Greek Labor Movement", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Sudermann, G. T. "Good Afternoon", typescript copy; 2 items (Box 139)
    - Tillich, Paul questionnaire-Nazi Germany, original typescript; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Tucker, J. R. "Brief Tucker Plan", original typescript; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Urzidil, Johannes
      - "Brot und Wein", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "Maxim Kopf's Prague Years", typescript copy; 2 items (Box 139)
      - "Polchau-Stenbock-Fermor", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Varley, Kirton "Stalemate in Korea", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Vegtel, Maddy "I am Looking for a Position", original typescript; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Viereck, Peter "The Poet in the Machine Age", published; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Von Brodfeld, Moriz
      - "Irgend Jermand", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "Der Liebe Augin", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Von Gebhardt, Hertha "The Last Days of Berlin", original typescript; 2 items (Box 139)
    - Von Kardorff, Katharina "Die grösste Zukunftsarmee der Welt", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Von Kleist, Henrich "Was Gilt Es Nach Diesem Kriege?", original typescript; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Von Moltke, Freya
      - "Aus Gransee-Mecklenburg wird uns brichtet", original typescript; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "Ersta Weisung an die Landesverweser", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "Germany", original typescript; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "Report Concerning Abduction of German Children to Soviet Russia", original typescript; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "UNNRA-Goods for Poland", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Von Moltke, Helmuth
      - "Exposé", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "The Last Letters of Count Helmuth James Von Moltke", published; 2 items (Box 139)
    - Wambaugh, Sarah autobiographical sketch, original typescript; 2 items (Box 139)
    - Warren, Dale "What's the Matter with Dick's Hatband?", original typescript; 2 items (Box 139)
    - Warren, Dale "Ferris Greenslet", published; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Wazyk, Adam "Poem for Adults", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Weisgal, Meyer
      - "Address on Palestine", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "Repertory Theatre in America", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Westbrook, Lawrence
      - "Avion Village-A Pattern for Modern Home Ownership", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "Let's Face the Music", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
    - Wilson, Margaret Thompson
      - "Goodbye Little Angel", original typescript; 3 items (Box 139)
      - "De-Streamline That Home", original typescript; 4 items (Box 139)
    - Winsloe, Christa
      - "Halbe Geige", pp. 1-119 typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "Halbe Geige", pp. 120-245 typescript copy; 1 item (Box 139)
      - "Heimat in Not", original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
      - "Der Freiheiskrieg", original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
      - "Thy Country Tis of Thee", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Woodhead, H. G. H. "A Missing Emperor", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Wolfers, Arnold
      - "Civic Liberties and Moral Standards in Post-Nazi Germany", original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
      - "Nazi Indoctrination, German Youth and Its Re-Education", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
      - "A United Europe?", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - X-Y-Z "A Second Front is Better Than No Front at All", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Zoshtchenko, Michael
      - "Black Cookies", (Summary) typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
      - "How Semyon Semyonovitch Fell in Love with an Aristocrat", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
      - "Without Lilacs", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
  - Manuscripts by others, By title (author unknown)
    - "Boden Reform", original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "The China Case", typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "Glossen zur Deutschen Kultur", original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "Heredity", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "Italy During the War-and Italy in the Peace", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "International P.E.N. Committee Meeting", typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Maxim Kopf, typescript copy; 3 items (Box 140)
    - "Kritiken", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Material-Für Eine "schmerzhafte uberprü fung der Ausen politik", typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "Die Mütter und die Spielkasinos", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "Neue Wege der geistigen Auseinandersetzung mit den Osten", typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "An Ode to a Full Life", original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - P A N "Vers ochs Prosa" anthology, published; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "Some Notes on a Proposed Weekly", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "Der Turm zu Babel", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - "We, the People", mimeographed; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Die Zeit des "schmerzilchen Uber püfens" ist da, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Unidentifiable German novel, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Unidentified, 12 items (Box 140)
  - Manuscripts about Dorothy Thompson, By author
    - Buchall, (Dorothy Thompson's Expulsion from Germany) mimeographed; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Bottome, Phyllis, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Cox, Mary Hodge review of The Courage to be Happy, original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Gunther, John, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Hoople, Ruth, original typescript; 2 items (Box 140)
    - Longmire, Carey, mimeographed; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Murray, Jeanne, original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Richards, Jean Marie, original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Strakosh, original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Vincent, John, original typescript; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Warren, Dale "An Unimaginary Conversation", typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Waters, Catherine and Warren, Hassmer, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 140)
    - Manuscripts about Dorothy Thompson, authors unknown; 19 items (Box 140)
- Oversized material
  - Honorary scrolls
    - Green leather case
      - Sarah Lawrence College
      - George Arents Medal, Syracuse University
      - Dartmouth College
      - Government of Syria
    - Red leather case
      - Tufts University
      - McGill University
      - Columbia University
      - Syracuse University
      - Kosciuszka Foundation, Copernican Award
    - White case
      - Jewish National Fund
      - Holy Land Emergency Liaison Program
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook 1: Photos, 1917-1925; Dorothy Thompson
    - Scrapbook 2: Photos, 1918-1927; Dorothy Thompson
    - Scrapbook 3: Photos, Dorothy Thompson, Sinclair Lewis, and Michael Lewis
    - Scrapbook 4: Photos, Dorothy Thompson, Sinclair Lewis, and Michael Lewis
    - Scrapbook 5: Photos, Dorothy Thompson and Sinclair Lewis
    - Scrapbook 6: Photos, Nobel Prize
    - Scrapbook 7: Photos, Dorothy Thompson in Israel
    - Scrapbook 8: Photos, Dorothy Thompson in Turkey
    - Scrapbook 9: Photos and clippings, Sinclair Lewis and the Nobel Prize
    - Scrapbook 10: Photos and clippings, Sinclair Lewis and the Nobel Prize
    - Scrapbook 11: Photostats, Sinclair Lewis's letters at Yale
    - Scrapbook 12: Clippings, Sauk Centre
    - Scrapbook 13: Maxim Kopf
    - Scrapbook 14: Maxim Kopf
    - Scrapbook 15: Maxim Kopf
    - Scrapbook 16: Maxim Kopf, Sketches
    - Scrapbook 17: Photos, Dorothy Thompson and Maxim Kopf
    - Scrapbook 18: Photos, Miscellaneous
    - Scrapbook 19: Photos, World War II
    - Scrapbook 20: Ledger, Stebbins Pond Club
    - Scrapbook 21: Clippings, 1931; See Microfilm materials: Clippings (English and German)
    - Scrapbook 22: Clippings, 1931; See Microfilm materials: Clippings (English and German)
    - Scrapbook 23: Clippings, 1932; Political; See Microfilm materials: Lippman columns
    - Scrapbook 24: Clippings, 1934-1935; about Dorothy Thompson; See Microfilm materials: Clippings about Thompson
    - Scrapbook 25: Clippings, 1933-1935; about Dorothy Thompson; See Microfilm materials: Clippings about Thompson
    - Scrapbook 26: Clippings, 1935-1936; about Dorothy Thompson; See Microfilm materials: Clippings about Thompson
    - Scrapbook 27: Clippings, 1937-1940; about Dorothy Thompson; Material may have been microfilmed. See Microfilm materials
    - Scrapbook 28: Clippings, about Dorothy Thompson; Material may have been microfilmed. See Microfilm materials
    - Scrapbook 29: Clippings, about Dorothy Thompson and Sinclair Lewis; Material may have been microfilmed. See Microfilm materials
    - Scrapbook 30: Clippings, book reviews by Dorothy Thompson; Material may have been microfilmed. See Microfilm materials
    - Scrapbook 31: Clippings, German; See Microfilm materials: Clippings (German language)
    - Scrapbook 32: Letterbook, 24 Jan 1939; Dorothy Thompson honorary dinner
    - Scrapbook 33: Records, 06 May 1941; Dorothy Thompson dinner
    - Scrapbook 34: Records-Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial Program, 15 Apr 1945
  - Microfilm materials, microfilmed in 1998
    - Scrapbooks, "On the Record" typescripts and published articles
      - 11 Jan 1937-20 Feb 1939 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 1)
      - 22 Feb 1939-14 Mar 1941 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 1)
      - 18 Mar 1941-16 Sep 1942 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 2)
      - 17 Mar 1936-16 Mar 1938 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 2)
      - 18 Mar 1938-24 Jun 1940 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 3)
      - 25 Jun 1940-02 Mar 1942 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 3)
      - 04 Mar 1942-01 Mar 1943 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 4)
      - 03 Mar 1943-08 May 1944 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 5)
      - 10 May 1944-27 Mar 1946 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 5)
      - 01 Apr 1946-18 Feb 1948 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 6)
      - 28 Feb 1948-30 Dec 1949 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 6)
      - 02 Jan 1950-16 Oct 1951 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 7)
      - 29 Oct 1951-30 Apr 1953 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 7)
      - 01 May 1953-31 Dec 1955 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 8)
      - 1956 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 9)
      - 1957 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 9)
      - 1958 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 10)
    - By-and-about Thompson and Lewis, 1931-1935 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 10)
    - "Dorothy Thompson" by Don Wharton, May 1937; Scribner's article (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 11)
    - Clippings about Thompson, Aug 1924-Jun 1935; Nov 1934-Jan 1935 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 11)
    - Clippings about Thompson, Oct 1935-Feb 1936; 1937,; undated (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 12)
    - Reviews of Thompson's books, 1939-1943; undated (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 12)
    - New York Times articles about Germany and Europe, circa 1931 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 12)
    - Clippings (German language), circa 1931 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 13)
    - Clippings (English and German), 1931 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 13)
    - Lippman columns, circa 1932 (Cabinet 5/2, Reel 13)